Kheel, Theodore W. Audio-Visual Materials 6021 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Theodore W. Kheel Audio-Visual Materials
1961-2001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel, Theodore W.
6021 AV
34.56 cubic feet
34.6 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
5767563
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 19, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 13, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Theodore Woodrow Kheel was said to be named for both Woodrow Wilson and his political rival Theodore Roosevelt, the result of a compromise between his politically differing parents. The settlement presaged a career in which Kheel would be tapped by mayors, governors, and presidents to settle disputes that were part of the nation's major political and social transitions from post-World War II to well into the 21st century.
Born in 1914 in Brooklyn, Ted Kheel attended public high school in the Bronx. He was awarded a Regents scholarship to Cornell University, where he attended an accelerated undergraduate law school program permitting him to earn a bachelor's and law degree in six years.
In private practice for a brief time after graduation from law school, Kheel soon was offered a position as a National Labor Relations Board attorney in Washington. Kheel's special talents as a mediator and his obvious political skills soon gave him the opportunity to move to a new war-time agency, where he was initially hired as principal mediation officer. By 1944, he had been appointed executive director of the National War Labor Board, with a staff of 2,500 who were hearing 150 disputes a week. Kheel's work at the WLB introduced him to the most important figures in the labor movement and key government officialscontacts he would use effectively in the future.
Following the end of World War II, Kheel returned to New York City and was drafted by Mayor O'Dywer to serve in the city's new Labor Relations Division, which Kheel came to head within a year. With the agreement of the mayor, Kheel was able to serve both in this position and maintain a separate, private law practice.
In 1949, Kheel was appointed to a part-time position as impartial chairman for an important segment of public transit in New York City, a position in which he would render 30,000 decisions through 1982. Also in 1949, Kheel became a partner in the New York law firm Battle, Fowler, Jaffin and Kheel. His skills in conflict resolution led an observer to remark that the firm's work began with a battle, ended by Kheel.
During his more than half a century of involvement in labor matters, Kheel was known above all else for his extraordinary ability to get feuding parties to make concessions to reach an agreement. In the important New York and national labor disputes which he would be called to mediate, Kheel's approach was to protect management rights and at the same time demand fairness to workers while also trying to protect the public interest in the issue.
Kheel's was frequently the voice of reason in settling a number of extremely difficult labor disputes of the 1960s and 1970s. Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr., turned to Kheel to help end the 114-day newspaper strike of 1962-63. Among his most infamous cases was the strike involving Mike Quill, head of the Transport Workers Union, who publically battled Mayor John V. Lindsay in 1965-66. Kheel's efforts also included helping coordinate bargainers and mediators during the 35-day New York City teachers' strike in 1968. President Lyndon B. Johnson summoned Kheel to Washington in 1964 to help mediate 10 days of feverish negotiations that prevented a nationwide rail walkout. Kheel would ultimately serve as a mediator and advisor for virtually every New York mayor from O'Dwyer to Beame, for the Kennedy-Johnson Administration, and other presidential administrations as well.
Kheel's interests in public issues were not limited to the labor sector. The policy disputes that came to his attention as a mediator and lawyer frequently cried out for larger solutions, and Kheel was not averse to using his considerable public presence and media contacts to seek redress, especially for what he viewed as past institutional injustices or misguided government actions. Although pressed to do so on a number of occasions, Kheel refused to run for elective office, preferring the role of a labor neutral and public advocate.
Kheel was also not averse to backing his powers of persuasion with legal action: a fierce advocate for public transit, he initiated a class action lawsuit over the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey's refusal to fund mass rail transit. His most sustained crusade for the public good related to his battle to limit commuter auto traffic and control highway building in New York City in favor of increased use of public transportation. Initially attacked by Port Authority officials and some city, state, and federal politicians of both parties, many of the solutions originally proposed by Kheel, including the concept of the subsidized fare, became public policy in later years.
An early supporter of the civil rights movement, Kheel and his wife Ann become involved with the New York Urban League in the 1950s. He served as its president in 1955 and as national president for four years. He worked with President Johnson on race issues and with Martin Luther King, Jr., in a libel suit against the New York Times. Kheel's mediation skills led to important strides in hiring African Americans in the airline industry. His reputation for sensitivity to minority issues resulted in his becoming involved in efforts to add civilians to the New York City Police Review Board in 1965. Kheel was also recruited as a peacemaker in the 1968 Ocean Hill-Brownsville Teachers dispute.
Even though Kheel handled disputes for transit workers, typesetters, and longshoremen, he reveled in the finer things in life, and dabbled as a restaurateur in fine food and was a patron of the fine arts.
He once owned a stake in Le Pavillon, a leading French restaurant in Manhattan, among others. He also represented numerous artists, including Robert Rauschenberg and Christo, and was the prime mover in the realization of the long-heralded Gates Project in Central Park in 2005.
He also made millions of dollars as an entrepreneur while facilitating sustainable economic and social change. He was the lead investor in the giant Punta Cana resort, transforming 30 miles of jungle in the Dominican Republic, and helped bring about the airport that opened that country to tourists and travelers.
Finding the solution to problems such as the impact of automation on the workplace, community disputes, and protecting a sustainable environment in which mankind will flourish, to name but a few, were the focus of Kheel's interest, enthusiasm, and financial support. He was the prime mover, bringing along like-minded citizens and specialists, in the creation of organizations to find solutions to the more intractable issues facing society. The Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, the Foundation on Automation and Employment (and its British counterpart), Automation House, the Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, and the Earth Pledge Foundation were among the most successful of such efforts. In the same vein, in collaboration with Price, Waterhouse in 1994, Kheel formed Prevention and Early Resolution of Conflicts, Inc. (PERC), now housed at Cornell ILR as Cornell/PERC Institute.
A prolific writer, Kheel is perhaps best known for his encyclopedic work on labor law. Throughout a career that was active almost until his death at age 96 in November 2010, he was able to balance, with amazing success, advocacy of the public good and the management of a successful law and mediation practice and other business and cultural interests.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5024: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration Awards 5776 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Interviews and Programs 6017: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021 MB: Theodore W. Kheel Memorabilia 6021 P: Theodore W. Kheel Photographs 6021/001: Theodore W. Kheel Correspondence 6021/003: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration files 6021/004: Theodore W. Kheel Legal Files 6021/005: Theodore W. Kheel Speeches and Articles 6021/006: Theodore W. Kheel Non-Profit Organization Files 6021/007: Theodore W. Kheel Subject Files 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles 6021/009: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021/010: Theodore W. Kheel Additional Files 6021/011: Theodore W. Kheel Punta Cana Files 6021/012m: Invitation and Program for the Theodore W. Kheel Memorial Service 6059 OH: Thomas Shactman Interviews with Theodore W. Kheel 6194 OH: College of Labor and Employment Lawyers Interview with Theodore W. Kheel 6196 OH: New York City Central Labor Council Interview of Theodore W. Kheel for Central Archives 6207 OH: CLEL Video Oral History Project
Kheel, Theodore Woodrow
5767563
- Theodore W. Kheel - American Arbitration Assn. Film 1961, 1 (Box 1)
- Pressline: Sidney Zion with Friends and Enemies -- 9/19/1980, 1 (Box 2)
- T. Kheel Collective Bargaining; 1) Session #3 (cont.); 2) Session #4 (part 1), 2 (Box 2)
- Women and Achievement - Philip Morris, YWCA, 3 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Master
- Hay Associates "Opinions" Acct. Annual Report & Wraparound, 4 (Box 2)
  Dub
- ETN Fundraiser, 5 (Box 2)
  Edited Master
- Western Union Bright star Teleconference Bumpers - 9/13/1983, 6 (Box 2)
- Leo Castelli Art Gala - 12/31/1982, 7 (Box 2)
- Woman between kids spots & Halston - tape #2, 1 (Box 3)
  TUB
- Double Entendre - Air Check -5/16/1981, 2 (Box 3)
- Closed Segment, 3 (Box 3)
- Lifemark Teleconference - Houston, 4 (Box 3)
- Unlabeled, 5 (Box 3)
- CBS Cable Affiliate Promo's - Corp. for Entertainment & Learning, 1 (Box 4)
- American Cancer Society "Women Need to Know" -, 2 (Box 4)
  Long version Part 2
- American Cancer Society "Women Need to Know", 3 (Box 4)
  Long version Part 1
- CNB Show, 4 (Box 4)
- Task Productions - Rangers Close-Up with Herb Brooks, 5 (Box 4)
  Show #13 - VT -- Protection Master
- TVB Tape #1 - Reels 1-13, 1 (Box 5)
- Beyond the Horizon Show #32, 2 (Box 5)
- Show F Music, 3 (Box 5)
- D.K.D. Productions "Mack Hanan", 4 (Box 5)
  edited Master; Segment 1
- D.K.D. Productions "Mack Hanan", 5 (Box 5)
  Edited Master; Segment 3
- Artists for NY #6, 6 (Box 5)
- Democratic Nat'l. Committee - Host Committee Report - Tues 8/12/1980, 7 (Box 5)
- Barbara Barondess in "The Open Cage", 1 (Box 6)
- Unlabeled, 2 (Box 6)
- Election Night Live - 1.Promos 2.Opening Credits 3.Commercial Music 4.Commercial Inserts, 3 (Box 6)
- Unlabeled, 4 (Box 6)
- Unlabeled, 5 (Box 6)
- Accounting Annual report & Wraparounds, 1 (Box 7)
- #180 The Best of Election Nite Live, 2 (Box 7)
- #183 Design problem for the elderly, 3 (Box 7)
- An Accounting of Video, 4 (Box 7)
- Lois, Pitts, Gershon -- George, Lois Historical Reel -- 5/2/1980, 5 (Box 7)
- Why Not Hungary -- 7/11/1984, 6 (Box 7)
- Dem. Nat'l. Comm. -- Host Committee Reports - Tues. 8/12/1980, 7 (Box 7)
- Valorin, Inc. - The Hidden Epidemic - Reel I, 8 (Box 7)
- Election Nite Live, 9 (Box 7)
- Pressline: Sidney Zion with Friends and Enemies -- 9/19/1980, 10 (Box 7)
- St. John's University - 11/23/1982, 11 (Box 7)
- Doug Davis - Double Entendre - 4/24/1981, 12 (Box 7)
- Host Committee Report, 13 (Box 7)
- Story: Brazilian Artist - 6/2/1981, 14 (Box 7)
- Democratic Nat'l. Committee - Host Committee Reports - Mon. Aug. 11, 1980, 15 (Box 7)
  Shooting Master
- Paris Tape - D. Davis -- Double Entendre -- April 28, 1981 -- Tape #1, 16 (Box 7)
- CBS Cable in Cabaret - Margaret Whiting Rev., 1 (Box 8)
- Jim Grav, Sample Reel -, 2 (Box 8)
  1.Rainbow; 2.Instant Nut; 3.Challenge; 4.Super Bowl; 5.Chewy Chocolate; 6.American Cancer; 7.Dan Lovett; 8.H. Rubenstein; 9.Revlon; 10.IBM
- Labor Looks at the 80's w/ Douglas Fraser, 3 (Box 8)
  type "C" - 1 inch
- Unlabeled, 4 (Box 8)
- I Prods. - Kids Music, 5 (Box 8)
- Advertising Show/Pre-pack, 6 (Box 8)
- Solar Energy - Nasarian, 7 (Box 8)
- Information Unlimited - Satellite Show - Helene Zimmerman, 1 (Box 9)
- SOHO TV - John Cage Show, 2 (Box 9)
  tape #41
- New York Women Against Rape (N.Y.W.A.R.), 3 (Box 9)
  tape no. 33 -- DUB
- Jazz Profiles - Migus & Monk /Sample reel, 4 (Box 9)
- Broadway Drama Guild "Trumpets Sounding", 5 (Box 9)
  tape # 40 - Master
- Castelli Gallery: Rauschenberg Exhibition Opening - 12/31/1982, 6 (Box 9)
- Diabetes: A New Perspective, 7 (Box 9)
- American Cancer Society presents "Women Need to Know" - 2/15/1980; Roll-in from Waldorf Remote - 9/5/1979, 8 (Box 9)
  Teach-in Edit Master - 9/5/1979
- Broadway Drama Guild - "Trumpets Sounding" by Gene Ruffini, 9 (Box 9)
  Reel 2 of 2 -- DUB
- Broadway Drama Guild - "Trumpets Sounding" by Gene Ruffini, 10 (Box 9)
  Reel 1 of 2 -- DUB
- Broadway Drama Guild - "Trumpets Sounding" by Gene Ruffini, 11 (Box 9)
  part 2 of 2 -- Master
- A&M Records Presents: Peter C. Johnson - Prod. No. 817, 12 (Box 9)
  DUB
- Sweet and Safe an answer to a Weight Watcher's Prayer; Contact: Lee Migliara, Danny Meenan, 13 (Box 9)
  9/10/1982
- Combating the Flu - 1261982, 14 (Box 9)
- Pasta the Thin Food: only 210 Calories - 8/30/1982, 15 (Box 9)
- N.Y. Arthritis Fdn. - the Arthritis Clinic - w/Dr. Storm Field, Host, 1 (Box 10)
- National Breast Cancer Teach-In, 2 (Box 10)
- Video Insert Segments for "Broadcasting Revolution", 3 (Box 10)
- Citizen's Committee Spots, 4 (Box 10)
- Hello- I must be going, 5 (Box 10)
- Improving Economic Understanding - 12/6/1982, 6 (Box 10)
- Fast Forward - Show #13 - TV, 7 (Box 10)
- Hello, I must be going, 8 (Box 10)
- Women need to know/teach-in edit - American Cancer Society, 9 (Box 10)
- American Cancer Society Presents - Women Need To Know, 10 (Box 10)
- Medical Program, 11 (Box 10)
- American Cancer Society - National Breast Cancer Teach-In -- 1/22/1980, 12 (Box 10)
- CNB-TV Development Dept. -- Presentation for American Lung Association, 13 (Box 10)
  1.Anti-Smoking PSA; 2.Fast Forward; 3.Fast Forward -- Edited Master
- Breast Cancer Teach-In -- Part I, 14 (Box 10)
- Nat. Breast Cancer Teach-In -- Grass Roots Local Follow-Up; Aspen, Colo., 15 (Box 10)
- Bound Feet - Freebaum Kong, 1980; 1 (Box 11)
  2nd Edit - AutoHse - 2/19/1980 -- Edited Master
- 1980 & 1981 - CBN-TV Demo Shows, 2 (Box 11)
- A Time to Begin / Lancome/Bloomies / Promos; Voltrak Test - w/Promo Header & Crawl - A.H. Compilation Tape, 3 (Box 11)
- The Greek World Show, 4 (Box 11)
- A Talk with King Viddr/w Theodore W. Kheel, 5 (Box 11)
- Intergroup Prod. - This is a hold-up, 6 (Box 11)
- A Conversation with King Vidor / w. Theodore W. Kheel, 7 (Box 11)
- Artist's Cable Project - Points of a Star / Ch. 2 - w/Rita Myers, 8 (Box 11)
- New York Scene: "Full Spectrum Lighting - 9/9/1977, 9 (Box 11)
- An Interview with Leroy Neuman, 10 (Box 11)
- An Interview with William Simon - w/Victor Riesel, 11 (Box 11)
- A Conversation with Leroy Neuman w/Theodore W. Kheel, 12 (Box 11)
- Off Off Broadway Tonight / Part 2 - w/Ruby Dee & Kevin McCarthy, 13 (Box 11)
- Off Off Broadway Tonight/Part I -- w/Ruby Dee & Kevin McCarthy, 14 (Box 11)
- Artists Cable Proj. Promo. Tape - C.N.B.T.V. - Jaime Davidovich (Proj. Dir.), 15 (Box 11)
- The Unconvention Show One - Part 2 - Monday, July 12, 1976, 5-7 pm, 1 (Box 12)
- The Unconvention Show Four - Part II (3rd tape - Following First 2 hours), Thursday, 7/15/1976, 2 (Box 12)
- The Unconvention Show Two - Part I, Tuesday, July 13, 1976, 5-7 pm, 3 (Box 12)
- The Unconvention Show Two, Part II, Tuesday, 7/13/1976, 4 (Box 12)
- St. John's University: "Poland Trip"; NTSC Submaster, 525/60 -- 6/27/1984, 5 (Box 12)
- Toby Likely Promo I Productions, 6 (Box 12)
- I Productions, 7 (Box 12)
- The Unconvention Show One, Part I, Monday, July 12, 1976, 5-7 PM, 8 (Box 12)
- The Joys of Wine Tasting, 9 (Box 12)
- The Unconvention Show 4, Part I, Thursday, 7/15/1976, 10 (Box 12)
- The Unconvention Show 4, Part II, Thursday, 7/15/1976, 11 (Box 12)
- The Joys of Wine Tasting-Air Copy, 12 (Box 12)
- The Unconvention Show Three, Part I, Wednesday, July 14, 1976, 5-7 PM, 13 (Box 12)
- The Unconvention Show 3, Part 2, Wednesday, July 14, 1976, 5-7 PM, 14 (Box 12)
- Unlabeled, 15 (Box 12)
  unboxed
- WCBS-TV, Ch.2, 9/19/1980 -- Re: NYS Lottery, 1 (Box 13)
- Hughes Air, Satellites and the Space Shuttle/What Keeps Them UP, 2/28/1984, 2 (Box 13)
- American Cancer Society, Film Inserts, Automation House 2/8/1980, 3 (Box 13)
- D.K.D. Co. 11/24/1981, 4 (Box 13)
  Reel 1B
- CBS Training Films Vol. 2, Vol. 1, Pt. 1&2, 5 (Box 13)
  Television Lighting (B&W); Color Brightness & Contrast; Color by Design
- Democratic National Convention - 8/13/1980, Reel 1, 6 (Box 13)
- TV Digest Version - 1980 Annual Report, 7 (Box 13)
  Spring 1981
- Civilisation - Arts Martiaux 2, 8 (Box 13)
- TW Kheel, 9 (Box 13)
  9/23 - (pt.3); 9/30 (pt.1) VanArsdale
- TW Kheel - 9/16/1980 Session 1 (pt.2), 10 (Box 13)
- TW Kheel - 9/16/1980 Session #1 (pt.3), 11 (Box 13)
- TWK - 9/30 "part 3"; 10/7 part 1, 12 (Box 13)
- TWK - 10/7 part 2, 13 (Box 13)
- Hughes - Satellites of Hughes "83, 14 (Box 13)
- Double Entendre - Double Entendre (May 16, 1981), 15 (Box 13)
  Edited Copy
- TW Kheel - Session #1 (pt.4) - 9/16/1980; Session #11 (pt.1), 1 (Box 14)
- TW Kheel - 9/30 (pt.2), 2 (Box 14)
- J.C. Penney Teleconference -- Jan '82, 1982; 3 (Box 14)
- Tele. Conf. 5/5/1981, 4 (Box 14)
- Center for Inter American Relations U.S./Cuba, 5 (Box 14)
- Democratic National Convention - 8/13/1980, Reel 3, 6 (Box 14)
- CNB-TV Development Dept. & SMPTE Presentation "Interactive TV" Synopsis Teleconferencing & Narrowcasting, 7 (Box 14)
- Artist's Television Network/Artist's Cable Project; Support Tape, 8 (Box 14)
- Anthology Film Archives Telethon, 9 (Box 14)
- Anthology Film Archives Telethon, 10 (Box 14)
- Anthology Film Anthology Archives Telethon, 11 (Box 14)
- SCUC Teleconference Aug. 12, 1982, Reel #2, 12 (Box 14)
- Diabetes: A New Perspective, 13 (Box 14)
  Master - Protection Copy
- TW Kheel, 14 (Box 14)
- Election Night Live - 11-4-1980, 15 (Box 14)
  Master Reel #3
- i-Productions -- Illusions cut 2; Never Look at You cut 2, 1 (Box 15)
  32 Master
- 1985 Creative Showcase, 2 (Box 15)
- Unique Sensation, 3 (Box 15)
  can't use -- reel one
- St. John's University: Poland Trip, 4 (Box 15)
  Master tape (European Standard)
- Doug Davis - Paris #1 -- 4/28/1981, 5 (Box 15)
- #4 Artists for N.Y., 6 (Box 15)
- #6 Artists for N.Y., 7 (Box 15)
- Paris "B" roll; Double Entendre, Doug Davis, 8 (Box 15)
- Great Image - B-Roll, 9 (Box 15)
- General Foods Commercial Compilation, 10 (Box 15)
  used for J. Hilton Inc.
- Democratic National Convention - 8/13/1980, 11 (Box 15)
  reel 2
- Election Night Live - 11/4/1980, 12 (Box 15)
  Master -- reel #2
- Democratic Nat'l. Committee - The Host Committee Reports - Monday, Aug. 11, 1980, 13 (Box 15)
- The Lost Million -- Roll in Reel B, 14 (Box 15)
  Noise Reduced Master
- The Devoted Group Inc., 15 (Box 15)
- 60 Minutes - 2/25/1979, 16 (Box 15)
  Cassette Piracy -- Pete Rose -- Mugging ------ Dub
- Western Union Bright Star Teleconference -- 9/13/1983, 17 (Box 15)
  Back-up
- Center for non broadcast TV - Behind the Sun - reel 1; Prot. Master from Studio A Shoot -- 9/14/1982, 1 (Box 16)
- Heublein: the Second Golden Age: Promo -- Hay Associates/Bruce Pennington, 2 (Box 16)
- The Evening Shaw, 3 (Box 16)
- C.N.B/T/V/., Inc. - Demo Reel #1A, 4 (Box 16)
- CNB TV DEMO, 5 (Box 16)
  Edit Master
- CNB-TV -- Promo. Reel Shooting Master, 6 (Box 16)
- C.N.B.T.V. - Demo Tape - Reel #1, 7 (Box 16)
- Blacks & the Mayor, 1980; 8 (Box 16)
  WNBC News; Gabe Pressman; Nov. 1980
- Labor Looks at the 80's; The JP Stevens Settlement with Jacob Siteinkman, 1980; 9 (Box 16)
  record date: 11/18/1980
- WTVS-TV MacNeil/Lehrer Report May 20, 1983 -- RE: Interview with Douglas Fraser, 10 (Box 16)
- C.N.B.C.T.V., Inc. - I.C.B. -- A Discussion of the 1980 Municipal Labor Negotiations w/Ted Kheel, 11 (Box 16)
- Annual Report 1980, 12 (Box 16)
- CNB-TV -- Behind the Sun -- Reel #2, 13 (Box 16)
- Hay Associates -- The Second Golden Age, 14 (Box 16)
- TW Kheel - Session #11 (pt.3) and 10/28 (pt.1), 1 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel - 10/28 Part 3; 11/11 Part 1, 2 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel -- 10/28 (pt.3), 3 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel - 11/18 (pt.2); Final Session 12/8 (pt.1), 4 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel - Session #11 (pt.2), 5 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel - 10/14 Pt.3; 10/21 Pt.1, 6 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel -- 10/21 Pt.2, 7 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel - 10/28 Pt.2, 8 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel -- 10/28 (Pt.4); 11/18 (pt.1), 9 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel - 10/14 Pt.2, 10 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel -- 10/7 )Pt.3; 10/14 Pt.1, 11 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel -- 10/21 Pt.3, 12 (Box 17)
- #2 Double Day, 13 (Box 17)
- #1 Double Day; Book Party -- 2/14/1984, 14 (Box 17)
- TW Kheel - 11/18 (pt.2, Final Session), 15 (Box 17)
- #3 Doubleday Party, 16 (Box 17)
- McGeorge School - Class #3 -- Broadcast of Controversial Issues, 1 (Box 18)
- McGeorge School - Class #2 -- Licensing of Broadcast Facilities & Reg. of Programming, 2 (Box 18)
- Channel "L" Compilatory Tape, 3 (Box 18)
- National Black Network/Overview Tape, 4 (Box 18)
- National Black Network, 5 (Box 18)
  Edited copy
- Home Money Management - Investing in the Mutuals/w Robert B. Rivel; Union Dime Savings Bank /w Monte Gordon & Saul Klaman, 6 (Box 18)
- The Great Transition with Herman Kahn & Brian Quin, 7 (Box 18)
  produced by Terran productions for Hudson Institute
- Home Money Management - Investing in the Mutuals /w Robert B. Rivel; Union Dime Savings Bank /w Monte Gordon & Saul Klaman, 8 (Box 18)
  3rd. Gen. Dub
- McGeorge School - Class #5 -- Cross Ownership & Political Broadcasting, 9 (Box 18)
- Lee Myles Commercials, 10 (Box 18)
- Meiji Shrine, 11 (Box 18)
- Shinjuku subcenter, 12 (Box 18)
- Shinjuku -, 13 (Box 18)
- M.I.T.I. with Counciler, 14 (Box 18)
- Videosynthesis / by Steve Rutt, 15 (Box 18)
- Amer. X-Press Travel Service - CABTV Commercials, 16 (Box 18)
- Saint Patrick's Day - Part 1, 1 (Box 19)
- Saint Patrick's Day - Part 2, 2 (Box 19)
- Election Night Live - 11/4/1980, 3 (Box 19)
  Master -- Reel #4
- Democratic National Convention - 8/11/1980 -- Reel III, 4 (Box 19)
- Democratic National convention -- 8/11/1980 -- Reel II, 5 (Box 19)
- Election Night Live - 11/4/1980, 6 (Box 19)
  Master Reel #1
- Simple Gifts - Program 1: Who Are They?; Program 2: Past and Present -, 1980; 7 (Box 19)
  Dub copy -- Record Date: 6/3/1980
- Fast Forward - PBS -- 7/30/1981, 8 (Box 19)
- Lois Pitts Gershon - Arby's Presentation Reel -- 3/22/1982, 9 (Box 19)
- Saint Patrick's Day - in the evening, 10 (Box 19)
- Great Image - Artisans Coop -- 9/26/1980, 11 (Box 19)
- Election Night Live - 11/4/1980, 12 (Box 19)
  Dub -- Reel #4
- Windsor, Ontario Assembly Plant for News Release, 13 (Box 19)
- River Town ---- EMPTY, 14 (Box 19)
- VCR Reel 4 - 8/14/1984 -- With Visual Code, 15 (Box 19)
- Toby Likely Players Promo, 1 (Box 20)
  i-Productions -- Master
- Self Pro (illegible handwriting), 2 (Box 20)
- Center Promo Photographs, 1978; 3 (Box 20)
  Shooting Master -- 11/16/1978
- Madison Square boys Club - Compilation Tape -- Liemer/Braune, 4 (Box 20)
- Girls Cam 2 -- i-Productions -- ISO Reel (cam 2), 5 (Box 20)
- Video Comm. Resources, 6 (Box 20)
- Exploring Language - 4 The Rhyme & Reason of Politics, 7 (Box 20)
- Hambrose Leasing, 8 (Box 20)
- Civilisation - Arts Martiaux, 9 (Box 20)
- Jenny Burton Promo by Skyfield prods, 10 (Box 20)
- McGeorge School of Law - Class #9 -- The Press & the 1st. Amendment, 11 (Box 20)